There we have learned about the counting, sort of.
Now, let's go and implement it in sign language.
And then in the next videos, we are going to solve this exercise in Java.
So we start by including the studio and we create a new function, void returning type and cold counting
sort.
It took into the parameter, the array that we are going to make a search for it and the size of this.
We start by making an inert array called output and then as default as default.
So finding the largest element of the Earth.
We start by making an Intel Max.
It into Max Equal, the array at index zero, we considered the first element is the largest element,
OK, because we have took the array at index here and we assign it to the max value.
Then we will create a a loop that starts from IE equal to one i.e. less than size and eye plus plus
if array at index i.e. greater than maximum than maximum equal to array at the index, I then make the
maximum equal to the first element, equal to the array at the index.
So if we find any number that that is great, a great element and the greater than the maximum that
we consider it as a first element, then change.
The first element, which is max, is equal to the earlier, then takes by the size of count must be
at least maximum +1.
OK.
We have learned this this is step because we said that we need to get the maximum variable for a first
step and that what we have done this is the first step.
The second step is making an array.
It is equal to the maximum.
Its size is equal to maximum +1.
But we cannot declare it as an inter-county maximum plus one in C as it does not support dynamic memory
allocation.
So its size is provided statically.
How to provide that it will be and count at index or count.
10.
We create count everyday with 10 variables.
We will see this why we have done that then because people that later on we will pass like a nine per
two meters or the greatest element would be none.
We will see this.
OK.
So don't don't stick with 10.
Initialize account array with all zeros, we initialize all the details, with all the elements, with
the arrows.
So four entire equal to zero eyeless the maximum, then we will start count at index are equal to zero.
Make all that numbers.
All of that counts.
Elements of this array is equal to zero.
Then this is the third step.
Store to the count of each element, we start making that count and see how many occurrences of the
element we start for entire equal to zero oil is then size higher plus plus we start by making count
at array and I i + +.
This is what we need to store to count for each element.
Store the cumulative count for each Saturday for entire equals to one I less than or equal to maximum.
May I plus plus go through all the elements and make the count at an equal the goal of the old count
of at index I plus count at index minus one.
And this is very important because we make a cumulative count for each of.
This is the fifth step now.
Find the index of each element of the original array in encountering and replace the elements in output
array that we have created here.
You remember it so for starting from size minus one.
I greater than or equal to zero I minus minus.
OK.
We start from the end the zero output at index count.
Of and X at index, I am minus one the size, this is very complicated case, I know.
But if you understand if you can can master it and you can remember it very fast.
OK, so follow the steps.
OK, this is steps.
Step number six.
OK.
Now, count decreased by now.
Copy the sorted elements into original array for I equal to zero.
I'll attend size day plus plus make the array at index.
I equals that say the element at index of the output.
OK, this is how we change and we we assign the new elements of each other now function to print an
element.
We have seen this function many times in the previous videos.
Just a for loop and that prints everything OK.
No driver code we create in the main a fun and a an int array four two two eight three three one.
And we make a size we could calculate the size by this and an equal size of array slept over or divided
by size of the index zero.
And we call the function counting source array and we pass and and we print it again.
And this is how we sort that array using counting sort algorithm.
OK.
It may be look complicated.
Please go back to the previous pages in order to see the animations and and understand how it functions,
how it works.
And I hope you understand it very well.
Now let's go and solve this exercise and make.